# Michael Alexander Giordano

[Salt Lake City, Utah] | [435-513-1582] | [magiordano77@gmail.com]

Results-oriented professional with Helio training and certifications in addition to 5+ years of experience in challenging development environments. Excellent communication and organizational abilities with a resourceful approach to solving diverse problems. Deadline-driven and knowledgeable professional with a strong desire to learn and contribute to team success.

#### **Education/Certifications**

15 credits towards Computer Science Minor, University of Utah
Bachelor of Science in Economics with emphasis in Statistical Analysis, University of Utah, 2017
Helio Training - Full Stack Web Development, Certification of Skill Proficiency, Certification of Course
Completion, 2019

### **Professional Experience**

Cru Kombucha | Salt Lake City, UT Sales Associate | July 2019 - Present

- Establish beneficial professional networks and partnerships to gain insight and campaign support resulting in long-term business relationships
- Work alongside retail representatives to boost sales by enhancing product presentations and advertising collateral
- Identify issues, analyzed information, and provided solutions to problems

Time off for Furthering Education | October 2018 - June 2019

Morgan Stanley | South Jordan, UT

Operations Project Analyst | September 2017 - September 2018

- Reported project cost analyses to enhance workflow and increase profits
- Monitored ongoing projects for adherence to prescribed timelines, suggesting operational changes where needed
- Determined root cause of problems and issues to implement courses of action required to implement solutions
- Wrote and distributed macros for the team using Visual Basic to ease the process of data entry and updating thousands of accounts
- Created an automated work distribution system to manage workflow for eleven team members

Time off for Furthering Education | February 2017 - August 2017

University of Utah IT | Salt Lake City, UT Front Desk Admin | July 2016 - January 2017

- Managed scheduling, mail distribution, communications, and other administrative support tasks for personnel
- Developed revisions to systems and procedures by evaluating operational practices and identifying improvement opportunities
- Identified issues and implemented troubleshooting techniques to alleviate downtime and system failure
- Conducted testing and troubleshooting for various software remotely and onsite for multiple server sets to maintain operational readiness

## **Additional Experience**

Nike Factory Store | Full-Time Athlete/Sales Associate

### **Core Competencies**

Interpersonal Communication, Time Management & Prioritization, User Experience Design, Web & Application Servers, Analytical Thinking, Complex Problem-Solving, Software Development Lifecycle, Search Engine Optimization, Data Modeling, User Research, Conflict Resolution, Application Development, Database Development & Management, Teamwork & Collaboration, Troubleshooting & Testing, Requirements Analysis, Project Coordination & Management, Computer Diagnostics, Tracking & Documentation, Customer Service Support, Documentation Development, System Performance Assessment, Microsoft Windows & Office, System Configuration, Delivery Management

#### **Technical Skills**

Git, Javascript Visual Basic, R, Node, HTML, React, Express, Bash, CSS, Java, Bootstrap